Tom Paulin papers, 1972-2008
Emory University
- Works by Tom Paulin, 1971-1994, Series 2; Boxes 9-22
  - Poetry, Subseries 2.2; Boxes 11-21, OP 1-2
    - The Argument at Great Tew (1985)
    - The Argument at Great Tew, MS drafts (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - The Argument at Great Tew, typescripts [2] (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - The Argument at Great Tew, printed versions [3] (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Fivemiletown (1987)
    - "André Chénier" (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - "Are Those F-111s?" (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - "Breez Marine" [variant title: "Ulysses' Wet Foreskin with Durex and Daily Mirror"] (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - "The Bungalow on the Unapproved Road" [variant title: "Strabane Bungalow"] (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - "Calque" ["Amerikanisch"] [See also "Jefferson's Virginia"] (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - "The Caravans on Lüneberg Heath" (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - "Chucking it Away" [variant title: "In der Fremde"] (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - "Defenester" (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - "The Defenstration of Hillsborough" [variant title: "Defenstration"] (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - "11/11/84" (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - "An English Writer on the French Revolution" (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - "Fivemiletown" (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - "From Landsflykt" (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - "'God Made the Catholics and the Armalite Made Us Equal'" (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - "The House of Jacob from a People of Strange Language" (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - "I Am Nature" (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - "Jefferson's Virginia" [includes "The Give-Thanks," "Those Gamey Locutions," "Plate Glass," and "April Fool"] [See also "Calque"] (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - "The Maiden That Is Makeless" (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - "Mount Stewart" (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - "Mythologies" (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - "Now for the Orange Card" [variant title: "Paulin's Palinode"] (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - "Peacetime" (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - "Really Naff" [variant title: "Gumbo"] (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - "The Red Handshake" (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - "The Rosetta Stone" (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - "Sure I'm a Cheat Aren't We All?" (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - "Symbolum" (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - "An Ulster Unionist Walks the Streets of London" (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - "Voronezh" (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - "Waftage: An Irregular Ode" (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - "Were the Rosenbergs Framed with a Pack of Jello?" (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - "Where's this Big River Come From?" (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - "Why The Good Lord Must Persecute Me" (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Fivemiletown, notebook (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Fivemiletown, "original typescript" (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Fivemiletown, typescript (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Fivemiletown, printer's galley proofs (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Fivemiletown, typesetting proofs (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Fivemiletown, typescript, reader's copy (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Fivemiletown, contents and acknowledgements drafts (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Fivemiletown, reviews (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Fivemiletown, reviews [scrapbook] (Box OP1)
    - Selected Poems 1972-1990 (1993)
    - Selected Poems 1972-1990, photocopy, annotated, with correspondence (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Selected Poems 1972-1990, reviews (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Walking A Line (1994)
    - "Across the Howrah Bridge" (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - "Air Plane" (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - "Almost There" (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - "American Light" (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - "The Bargain Bed" (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - "Basta" (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - "A Belfast Bildungsroman" (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - "Cadmus and the Dragon" (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - "Circumstantial" (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - "[Cush]" (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - "Don't" (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - "51 Sans Souci Park" (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - "The Firhouse" (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - "Going Back to the Sand Cabin" (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - "A Hard Sell" (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - "Hegel and the War Criminals" (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - "History of the Tin Tent" (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - "The Instant Friendship" (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - "The Ivy Restaurant" (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - "Kevin O'Higgins and the Justice Squad" [variant title: "Salus Populi Suprema Lex"] (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - "Kinship Ties" (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - "L" (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - "A Last Gesture" (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - "Linda Nicklin" (Box 16, Folder 24)
    - "The Lonely Tower" (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - "Loyal as Ever" (Box 16, Folder 26)
    - "Macaulay Jail" (Box 16, Folder 27)
    - "Matins" (Box 16, Folder 28)
    - "Middle Age" (Box 16, Folder 29)
    - "Naa;f" (Box 16, Folder 30)
    - "The Natural Order" (Box 16, Folder 31)
    - "The New Year" (Box 16, Folder 32)
    - "On the Windfarm" (Box 16, Folder 33)
    - "The Other England" (Box 16, Folder 34)
    - "Painting the Carport" (Box 16, Folder 35)
    - "Painting with Sawdust" (Box 16, Folder 36)
    - "Palestinian Free State" [variant title: "For the Intifada"] (Box 16, Folder 37)
    - "A Poor Useless Creature" (Box 16, Folder 38)
    - "Portnoo Pier" (Box 16, Folder 39)
    - "Priming the Pump" (Box 16, Folder 40)
    - "Rooks" (Box 16, Folder 41)
    - "Serial Lover in the Woodyard" (Box 16, Folder 42)
    - "Soldier and Packman" (Box 16, Folder 43)
    - "Sparrowgrass" (Box 16, Folder 44)
    - "The Sting" (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - "A Taste of Blood" (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - "That's It" (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - "Unnatural Object" (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - "What's Natural" (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - "Wisdom's Dark Grove" (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Walking a Line, typescript, corrected (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Walking a Line, page proofs, corrected (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Walking a Line, proofs (photocopied), with annotations (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Walking a Line, printed materials (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Walking a Line, miscellaneous fragments (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Walking a Line, associated materials (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Walking a Line, reviews (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Walking Lines (1997; audio cassette)
    - Walking Lines, contents list and notes (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - The Wind Dog (1999)
    - "Before Apple-Picking" (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - "Bournemouth" (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - "Chagall Designs Christy Mahon's Costume" (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - "Chagall in Ireland" (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - "?Chesterfield" (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - "Craqulure" (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - "Cuas" (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - "Door Poem" (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - "Drumcree Four" (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - "Drumcree Three" (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - "The Emigration of the Poets" (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - "The English Republic" (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - "Fortogiveness" (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - "Le Crapaud" (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - "Man Walking the Stairs" (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - "Marc Chagall, Over the Town" (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - "My Problem" (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - "My Skelf" (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - "A Naïve Risk" (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - "Not Musical" (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - "Oxford" (Box 18, Folder 21)
    - "Paris Ink Sketch" (Box 18, Folder 22)
    - "The Quinn Brothers" (Box 18, Folder 23)
    - "Sarum's Prize" (Box 18, Folder 24)
    - "Sentence Sound" (Box 18, Folder 25)
    - "Theta is Better" (Box 18, Folder 26)
    - "The Unholy One?" (Box 18, Folder 27)
    - "Utile as Fetish" (Box 18, Folder 28)
    - "The Wind Dog" (Box 18, Folder 29)
    - The Wind Dog, notebooks [2] with manuscript drafts (Box 18, Folder 30)
    - The Wind Dog, typescript, corrected (Box 18, Folder 31)
    - The Wind Dog, galley proofs, photocopied (Box 18, Folder 32)
    - The Wind Dog, galley proofs, photocopied, with corrections (Box OP2)
    - The Wind Dog, printed materials (Box 18, Folder 33)
    - The Wind Dog, miscellaneous [including associated correspondence] (Box 18, Folder 34)
    - Uncollected poems by Tom Paulin [Drafts are both MS and TS unless otherwise noted]
    - "Abandoned Novels" [originally filed with The Strange Museum] (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - "After Reading Five Thousand Poems by Anon." [originally filed with Fivemiletown] (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - "Air and Exercise" [originally filed with Fivemiletown] (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - "Almost There" [originally filed with Walking a Line] (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - "And the Night in which it was Said" [originally filed with Fivemiletown] (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - "At a Military Hospital" [originally filed with The Strange Museum] (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - "The Atlantic Approaches" [originally filed with Walking a Line] (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - "At Lockjaw Hall" [originally filed with The Strange Museum] (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - "At Mill with Slaves" [originally filed with Fivemiletown] (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - "At Simla" [originally filed with The Strange Museum] (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - "At the World's End" [deleted from A State of Justice] (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - "Bar-Room Conversation" [originally filed with The Strange Museum] (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - "Belling the Cat" [Piers Plowman translation] [originally filed with Fivemiletown] (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - "Beyond the Pale" [originally filed with The Strange Museum] (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - "Boxed" [deleted from A State of Justice] (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - "Cadmus and the Dragon" [published in Hoffman and Lasdun, After Ovid], drafts and associated correspondence (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - "Cain's City" [originally filed with The Strange Museum] (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - "Cézanne and the Art Object" [originally filed with Fivemiletown] (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - "Chez Them" [originally filed with The Strange Museum] [with "Voyeur"] (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - "The Chosen" (Box 19, Folder 20)
    - "Cities of the Plain" [deleted from A State of Justice] (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - "Civil Comfort" [originally filed with The Strange Museum] [See also Subseries 2.4, Criticism: Essays and reviews, "Source"] (Box 19, Folder 22)
    - "Coda" [originally filed with The Wind Dog] (Box 19, Folder 23)
    - "Crossing the Equator" [originally filed with The Wind Dog] (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - "Dead Labourers" (Box 19, Folder 25)
    - "Deceptions, Promises" (Box 19, Folder 26)
    - "De Valera and the Ulster Question" [originally filed with Fivemiletown] [See also Uncollected poems, "Document No. 3"] (Box 19, Folder 27)
    - "A Discarded Prime Minister" [originally filed with The Strange Museum] (Box 19, Folder 28)
    - "Discoveries" [originally filed with The Strange Museum] (Box 19, Folder 29)
    - "Discovery of Bishop MacNeice's House" [deleted from A State of Justice] (Box 19, Folder 30)
    - "Document No. 3" ["The Reporter at the Peace Conference"] [See also Uncollected poems,: "De Valera and the Ulster Question" and "Paisley and the Irish Question"; and Subseries 2.3, Prose: "The Lodge of the Nine Muses"] (Box 19, Folder 31)
    - "Document No. 3" ["The Reporter at the Peace Conference"], notebook (Box 19, Folder 32)
    - "Dwyer" [originally filed with The Strange Museum] (Box 19, Folder 33)
    - "The Elgin Marbles" [originally filed with Walking a Line] (Box 19, Folder 34)
    - "Elsewheres" (Box 19, Folder 35)
    - "The Emperor of the North" [deleted from A State of Justice] (Box 19, Folder 36)
    - "Endogamy" [originally filed with Fivemiletown] (Box 19, Folder 37)
    - "Enlightenment" [deleted from A State of Justice] (Box 19, Folder 38)
    - "Epithalamia" (Box 19, Folder 39)
    - "The Equipment" [originally filed with The Strange Museum] (Box 19, Folder 40)
    - "Ethnic Cleansing" [originally filed with Walking a Line] (Box 19, Folder 41)
    - "The Eye's Parish" [originally filed with The Strange Museum] (Box 19, Folder 42)
    - "February's Child" (Box 19, Folder 43)
    - "Finger the Liberty Bell" [originally filed with Fivemiletown] (Box 19, Folder 44)
    - "First Day in Andalucia" [originally filed with Walking a Line] (Box 19, Folder 45)
    - "Flight" (Box 19, Folder 46)
    - "For a Biography of Lord Randolph" [originally filed with Fivemiletown] (Box 19, Folder 47)
    - "Freedoms" [originally filed with The Strange Museum] (Box 19, Folder 48)
    - "The French Academy" [originally filed with The Strange Museum] (Box 19, Folder 49)
    - "'From Popery, Brass Money and Wooden Shoes'" [originally filed with Fivemiletown] (Box 19, Folder 50)
    - "A Geek" [originally filed with Fivemiletown] (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - "Half-Homage" [originally filed with The Strange Museum] (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - "Hearts of Darkness" [originally filed with Fivemiletown] (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - "High Society" [originally filed with The Strange Museum] (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - "The Hillsborough Treaty" [originally filed with Fivemiletown] (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - "The Hospital for Sick Children" (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - "Household Diary" [originally filed with Walking a Line] (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - "Image" [deleted from A State of Justice] (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - "Imaginary Bailiffs" [originally filed with The Strange Museum] (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - "Inheritance" [originally filed with The Strange Museum] (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - "The Instant Friendship" [originally filed with Walking a Line] (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - "Irish History" [originally filed with Liberty Tree] (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - "Irish Unity" [and Or the Union] [originally filed with Fivemiletown] (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - "'I, Too, Was a Believer'" [originally filed with The Strange Museum] (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - "James 'Mick' Magennis VC" (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - "Kicking the Heirarchy" [originally filed with Fivemiletown] (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - "Kind of Dasein" [originally filed with Walking a Line] (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - "A Kind of Local" [deleted from A State of Justice] (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - "Lagan Gang, Lagan Gangs" [originally filed with Fivemiletown] (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - "The Lame Ferryman" [deleted from A State of Justice] (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - "The Last Journalist is Leaving" ["No More Photographs"] [originally filed with The Strange Museum] (Box 20, Folder 21)
    - "Last Verses" [originally filed with The Strange Museum] (Box 20, Folder 22)
    - "Let No Man Write My Epitaph" [originally filed with Fivemiletown] (Box 20, Folder 23)
    - "Long Distance" [originally filed with The Strange Museum] (Box 20, Folder 24)
    - "Making a Bed" [originally filed with Fivemiletown] (Box 20, Folder 25)
    - "Making Scarce" [originally filed with Walking a Line] (Box 20, Folder 26)
    - "Man and a House" [originally filed with The Strange Museum] (Box 20, Folder 27)
    - "Map Detail" [deleted from A State of Justice] (Box 20, Folder 28)
    - "Missing" [originally filed with The Strange Museum] (Box 20, Folder 29)
    - "Motoring" (Box 20, Folder 30)
    - "Mr. Johnston" [originally filed with Fivemiletown] (Box 20, Folder 31)
    - "Mug Poem" [originally filed with Walking a Line] (Box 20, Folder 32)
    - "Nail Poem" [originally filed with The Wind Dog] (Box 20, Folder 33)
    - "Near the Christadelphians" [deleted from A State of Justice] (Box 20, Folder 34)
    - "Neither Here nor There" [originally filed with Fivemiletown] (Box 20, Folder 35)
    - "Newland Park" [originally filed with Walking a Line] (Box 20, Folder 36)
    - "Night Out" [originally filed with Walking a Line] (Box 20, Folder 37)
    - "No Compensation" [originally filed with The Strange Museum] (Box 20, Folder 38)
    - "Old Faces" [originally filed with The Strange Museum] (Box 20, Folder 39)
    - "The Old Life" [deleted from A State of Justice] (Box 20, Folder 40)
    - "Opposite of Ballylumford" [originally filed with The Strange Museum] (Box 20, Folder 41)
    - "Outside the Law" (Box 20, Folder 42)
    - "Paisley and the Irish Question" [originally filed with Fivemiletown] (Box 20, Folder 43)
    - "Pli de Lin" [originally filed with Fivemiletown] (Box 20, Folder 44)
    - "Pollock" [originally filed with Fivemiletown] (Box 20, Folder 45)
    - "Portrait" [originally filed with The Strange Museum] (Box 20, Folder 46)
    - "Prayer" [originally filed with The Strange Museum] (Box 20, Folder 47)
    - "The Pretend Father" [originally filed with Fivemiletown] (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - "Private View" (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - "Removal" [deleted from A State of Justice] (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - "Responsibilities" [deleted from A State of Justice] (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - "The Result" [originally filed with The Strange Museum] (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - "Rockingham County" [originally filed with Fivemiletown] (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - "Rosetta" [originally filed with Fivemiletown] (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - "Separated Unto the Gospel" [originally filed with Fivemiletown] (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - "Shakespeare's Latest Play" [originally filed with Walking a Line] (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - "Small Envy" [originally filed with Walking a Line] (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - "Somewhere Else" [originally filed with The Strange Museum] (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - "Space" [originally filed with The Strange Museum] (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - "Stranmillis" [originally filed with Walking a Line] (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - "Summits, Benches" [originally filed with The Strange Museum] (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - "Sunday Bedroom" [deleted from A State of Justice] (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - "The Temptation" [originally filed with The Strange Museum] (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - "They" [originally filed with The Strange Museum] (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - "To a Political Poet" [originally filed with Fivemiletown] (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - "To the Girl with the Golden Bum" (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - "Voyeur" [deleted from A State of Justice] (Box 21, Folder 20)
    - "Waiting for the Lexicographer" [originally filed with Fivemiletown] (Box 21, Folder 21)
    - "A Walk to Pubble Shrub Gardens" [originally filed with Fivemiletown] (Box 21, Folder 22)
    - "Where Blood has Dried" [originally filed with The Strange Museum] (Box 21, Folder 23)
    - "Winter Becoming Spring" [deleted from A State of Justice] (Box 21, Folder 24)
    - "The Writing Lark: A Letter to John Clare" (Box 21, Folder 25)
    - "The Writing Lark: A Letter to John Clare," notebook with drafts (Box 21, Folder 26)
    - "You've Guessed It" [originally filed with Walking a Line] (Box 21, Folder 27)
    - Untitled ["Cornelius has come into the classroom with an egg"] [originally filed with Fivemiletown] (Box 21, Folder 28)
    - Untitled ["Dear Mac.. ."] [originally filed with Walking a Line] (Box 21, Folder 29)
    - Untitled ["Dear Tina.. ."] (Box 21, Folder 30)
    - Untitled ["The wind in pine forests.. ."] [deleted from A State of Justice] (Box 21, Folder 31)
    - Unidentified poems and fragments originally filed with The Strange Museum (Box 21, Folder 32)
    - Unidentified poems and fragments originally filed with Liberty Tree (Box 21, Folder 33)
    - Unidentified poems and fragments originally filed with Fivemiletown (Box 21, Folder 34)
    - Typescript set of early poems (Box 21, Folder 35)
    - Unidentified poems and fragments (Box 21, Folder 36)
  - Prose, Subseries 2.3; Box 22
    - "Belfast Oysters" (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - "Diary" [ LRB, 24 August 1995] (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - "Diary" [ LRB, 18 May 1998] (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - "Diary" [ LRB, 18 May 1998], notes and correspondence (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - "Diary" [ LRB, 16 Sept 1999] (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - "The Egyptian Girl" [ Quarto, February 1980] (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - "A Hot Opera" (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - "The Lodge of the Nine Muses" [includes printed pamphlet] [See also Subseries 2.2: Uncollected poems by Tom Paulin: "Document No. 3"] (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - "They Are As Intimate With Each Other As With Their Underpants" (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Unidentified draft ["An old man looks at the river.. ."] (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Criticism, Subseries 2.4; Boxes 23-39
    This subseries includes Tom Paulin's monograph, The Day-Star of Liberty, as well as separate sections on his essays and reviews as well as his lectures. Researchers should be aware that sometimes Paulin's lectures grow out of his reviews and essays, and vice-versa, and so there may be some review and essay material filed with certain lectures. In the essay and review section below, individual essays are filed initially, followed by book-length collections of essays.
    - Monograph: The Day-Star of Liberty: William Hazlitt's Radical Style
    - Introduction, drafts (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Chapter One, "A State of Projection," drafts (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Chapter Two, "Republican Poetics," drafts (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Chapter Three, "Celebrating Hutcheson," drafts (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Chapter Four, "Sheer Plod: Whig Prose," drafts (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Chapter Five, "The Serbonian Bog," drafts (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Chapter Six, "The Poetry in Prose," drafts (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Chapter Seven, "Southey's Organ of Vanity," drafts (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Chapter Eight, "Coleridge the Aeronaut," drafts (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Chapter Nine, "Blind Orion," drafts (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Chapter Ten, "Hazlitt faciebat: The Spirit of the Age," drafts (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Chapter Eleven, "Vehemence versus Materialism: The Spirit in the Age," drafts (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Chapter Twelve, "Great Plainness of Speech," drafts (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Epilogue, drafts (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - TSS of individual chapters, annotated by proofreader (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - TS, annotated (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - TS, annotated (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Complete TS [chapters 1-4] (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Complete TS [chapters 5-12] (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Complete TS [notes, bibliography and relevant correspondence] (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Galley Proofs (photocopy), annotated [p. i-187] (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Galley Proofs (photocopy), annotated [p. 188-end] (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Galley Proofs, annotated [p. i-118] (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Galley Proofs, annotated [p. 119-248] (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Galley Proofs, annotated [p. 249-end] (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Publisher's uncorrected proof (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Research notes [1] (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Research notes [2] (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Research notes [3] (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Research notes [4] (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Research notes [5] (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Research notes [6] (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Hazlitt chronology notebook (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - "Chronology" drafts (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - "Bibliography" drafts (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - "Index" drafts (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Reviews (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Essays and reviews
    - "Antigone," TS drafts (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - "The Art of Criticism," drafts (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - "The Art of Criticism," full set of newspaper clippings (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - "The Art of Criticism," notes (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - "The Art of Criticism," research materials (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - "The Art of Criticism," correspondence (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Defoe, Robinson Crusoe proposal (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - "Ephemeral Voices" [rev. of Island Cross-Talk by Tomás O'Crohan] (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - "Laureate of the Free Market? Ted Hughes," typescript (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - "Laureate of the Free Market? Ted Hughes," research and correspondence (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - "A New Look at the Language Question," manuscript versions (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - "A New Look at the Language Question," typescript versions (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - "A New Look at the Language Question," photocopy (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - "A New Look at the Language Question," associated correspondence and materials (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - "A New Look at the Language Question," research materials and notes (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - "Paisley's Progress," galley proof and printed version (Box 31, Folder 6)